

Taeyoung Kim

ROBOTICS · PERCEPTION ENGINEER

340, Mokdongseo-ro, Yangcheon-gu, Seoul, 08089, Republic of Korea

 $\square \ (+82) \ 10-9686-8177 \ | \ \blacksquare \ tyoung96@naver.com \ | \ \ \mbox{\em α taeyoung96.github.io} \ | \ \ \mbox{\em Ω} \ Taeyoung96$

"Nothing ventured, nothing gained."

Summary.

This is Taeyoung Kim, who wants to become an autonomous driving or robotics Perception engineer. My research interests are Computer Vision and SLAM. I like to take on challenging tasks and I like to grow up with my colleagues around me. That's why I record and share what I did on my Github or Technical Blog. I'm also interested in contributing open-source projects.

Research Interests

Computer Vision Object Detection, Segmentation, Depth Estimation, 3D reconstruction

SLAM Visual SLAM, Visual Odometry

Education

B.S. IN SCHOOL OF ROBOTICS

Kwang Woon University

• Current GPA: 4.09 / 4.50, Current Major GPA: 4.40 / 4.50

• Club: BARAM (Robotics Academic Group) - [2020 Staff], DAISY (English Conversation Club) - [2019 Spring President]

Work Experience_

Computer Vision Lab @Korea Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

Seoul, S.Korea

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2022 (Expected)

UNDERGRADUATE LAB INTERN (ADVISOR: PROF. SANGPIL KIM)

Mar. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- Research on Computer Vision using an Event camera
- Event data processing using ESIM

KIST(Korea Institute of Science and Technology)

Seoul, S.Korea

STUDENT INTERN (ADVISOR : DR. KANGGEON KIM)

Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Research on Monocular Depth Estimation
- Participated in KIST disinfect robot (AI Disinfection Robot) project [Video]

Image Process System Lab @Kwang Woon Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

Undergraduate Lab Intern (Advisor: Prof. Donggyu Sim)

May. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Research on Image Processing based on Deep learning
- Participated in seminars related to Deep Learning and Image Processing

Publication

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE

UR2021 (Work in progress), Taeyoung Kim, Omer Faruk Ince, JongBeom Baek, Jun-Sik Kim, KangGeon Kim, "Dense Monocular SLAM applied Depth Estimation" - [Paper], [Video]

KROS

DOMESTIC CONFERENCE

KROS2021, TaeHwan Kim, Taeyoung Kim, GiJae Lee, KangGeon Kim, 2021.5

KROS

"Recognition of disinfection targets and generation of semantic map for disinfection robot" - [Paper] **KSPC2020**, Naseong Kwon, Taeyoung Kim, Subin Kim, Joohyung Byeon, Jongsuk Lee, Donggyu Sim,

2020.9 "Luma Mapping with Chroma Scaling based on CNN feature map for VVC subjective quality improvement" -

IEIE

[Paper]

Honors & Awards

AWARDS

2020.11 Dean's L	ist , for Academic Excellence	KwangWoon Univ.
2020 0 Eth Di ae	5th Place on B-track , Korea Health Datathon 2020	NAVER CLOUD
2020.9 5th Plac		PLATFORM
2019.10 Dean's L	ist, for Academic Excellence	KwangWoon Univ.

Honors

2021-2	National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship ,	Korea Student Aid
2021-1	for the students, those who have been recommended by the university (Full tuition Scholarship)	Foundation
2020-2	National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship ,	Korea Student Aid
2020-1	for the students, those who have been recommended by the university (Full tuition Scholarship)	Foundation
2019-2	Full tuition Scholarship, for Top seat last semester	KwangWoon Univ.

Skills

Programming C++/C, Python, JAVA, Matlab Framework Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras DevOps Git, Docker, ROS

Extracurricular Activity

Languages Korean, English

Technical Blogs

WRITERS May. 2020 - Present

You can easily access the blog using [this link].

- Writing some posts about lecture summary, paper review, some tips for developments.
- To share what I have studied with others and to remember it longer.

2021 Open Source Contribution Academy

Ministry of Science and ICT

MENTEE

Aug. 2021 - Present

KwangWoon Univ.

Mar. 2021 - Jun.2021

Sep. 2020 - Nov. 2020

Apr. 2020 - Jun. 2020

- I am in the process of translating a Pytorch tutorial into Korean that I want to contribute to the spread of PyTorch.
- Using Github, I developed the ability to collaborate and contribute to open source.
- The open source repository I've contributed can be found [here].

CLOVA AI RUSH 2021 NAVER AI Lab, NAVER CLOVA

PARTICIPANT May. 2021 - Jun.2021

- Only 150 students are allowed to participate in this project.
- I developed my own deep learning model related to multi-label classification.
- I ranked 30th on Project 1-3.

PERSONAL TOY PROJECT

PERSONAL TOY PROJECT

2021 Spring Capstone Design

PROJECT

- I made a wireless charging electric vehicle charging robot.
- I designed the control input algorithm, trained deep learning model, and developed the ROS package.
- The source code related to this project is on my [Github repository].

Monocular Depth Estimation with ORB-SLAM2

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

• I was curious about the performance of the recent depth estimation model.

Tused 'Monocular Depth Estimation with Transfer Learning pretrained MobileNetV2' model and applied to ORB-SLAM2

also compared with ORB-SLAM2(Monocular mode), ORB-SLAM2(RGB-D mode) • The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].

Runner Alarm System based on Deep Learning

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

- · I wanted to distinguish between walking children and running children with an object detection model.
- When children are running for an amount of time, a beep sounds.
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].

OCTOBER 11, 2021 TAEYOUNG KIM · CURRICULUM VITAE